

LEONARDO J. MACEDO

Software Engineer | SysAdmin | BSS (Telco) Consultant



ABOUT ME

About **9 years work experience** in support, operations and IT consulting for OSS/BSS Telco systems.

In the recent years, being part of production team as subject-matter expert of rating chain process, part of Ericsson Billing Convergent Solution (BSCS-IX) in technical issues, business support, deployments, and automation developer (scripting).

Critical spirit and problem-solving skills, having participated actively of risk and crisis management processes, proposing definitive and/or alternative technical solutions, always focused on service availability and service delivery as well as service level agreements attendance.

Currently, working in software engineer master's thesis about benefits of Machine Learning to improve **ITSM incident tickets classification process**.

EDUCATION

M.Sc in Software Engineering (In progress) | 2017 - 2019

Faculty of Engineering, University of

B.Sc in Computer Science | 2007 -

São Judas Tadeu Faculty - São Paulo, Brazil

CONTACT

in macedojleo

macedojleo@gmail.com

macedojleo

🥱 macedojleo.github.io

S leonado.macedo

EXPERIENCE

SEP, 2017 - PRESENT

Master degree student

Faculty of Enginering, Universisty of Porto

Master's Degree in Software Engineering by the Faculty of Engineering of the University of Porto in Portugal.

At this time, developing work thesis related to "Automation ITSM ticket classification process through Machine Learning and Natural Language Processing (NLP)".

SEP, 2009 - AUG, 2014

IT BSS Consultant

Orga Systems | TIM Brazil

OPSC GOLD **BSS IT consultant/production** analyst, supporting business areas and guarantee Rating Chain service delivery.

Tickets backlog attendance compliance SLA, projects implementation, end-to-end problems workflow, provide and maintaining system and environment monitoring system, scripting (automating processes), environment administration (backup, purge, resource utilization, and processing strategy) and system metrics performance analysis.

AUG, 2014 - JUN, 2017

IT Specialist

Nextel Telecomunicações

Ericsson BSCS-IX SME for Rating chain modules, resposible for incident backlog attendance, workload, SLA compliance and support revenue teams through technical analysis.

Service Owner in Change-Advisory Board (CAB), rollout strategies, implementation, monitoring, evidence collection, ETL for business reports, regulatory compliance (ANATEL), and automation operational processes (scripting).

FEB, 2008 - SEP, 2009

Production Analyst

Ericsson | TIM Brazil

Ericsson Multi Mediation telco system production analyst, assuring that all CDRs were collected from different network elements, processing (formatting, aggregation, dupcheck), and delivery as business rules and regulatory compliance for each BSS system. Incident tickets backlog attendance, troubleshooting, RFC technical validation and implementation, monitoring processes, Shell script development for automation, and Business support.

FREE COURSES

2019	2018	2015
Mastering Ansible (in progress) UDEMY	Python for Engineering NTITEC (FEUP)	Oracle Database 11G Adm Ka Solution
2014	2006	2006
ITIL V3 - Foundations Ka Solution	Cisco CCNA V3 Senac - SP	Linux System Administrator Senac - SP

OPEN SOURCE AND ACADEMIC PROJECTS

Ansible CI Tutorial

github.com/macedojleo/DOCKER_ANSIBLE

BDH - Monitorize Unix and Linux FS consuption

https://macedojleo.github.io/BDH/

7th Talk-A-Bit Tech Conference - Porto

http://talkabit.org/

Automate IT Incident Management Process

macedojleo.github.io/Aprendizagem-Computacional-em-ITSM/

CosnFlix - Video Streaming Service

https://github.com/macedojleo/COSNFLIX

Pomar - Organic Food APP

https://gitlab.com/gigantedocil/pomar-mobile-

SKILLS

Development	IT Infrastructure	Languages
Shell Script & AWK	Linux & Unix	English
Python	Docker & Docker Compose	Spanish
Git & GitHub	Oracle SQL	Portuguese
Text Markup Languages	BMC Control-M	